All right, we are going to go over real quick how
to fill out one of these purchase contracts.
So to start off buyer, that's your entity seller.
That's your entity. Premise address. That's the address.
That city right here, county.
You can find all this information on your own.
Um, based off the address of the property,
the legal description,
that is gonna be found on Maricopa County Assessor.
Um, for this specific county, um, if we're looking at
a property in Arizona,
it's gonna be Maricopa County Assessor.
It depends on what, um, county the property is in.
If it's in Atlanta, there's all these different counties.
You can go find the legal description.
Um, and then purchase price is right here.
The earnest money right here.
Um, say the purchase price, just for example,
sake is 3 million.
And the earnest money is a hundred thousand.
Due at closing is the purchase price minus earnest money.
Whatever's left due at closing. So it'd be 2.9 million.
Um, let's keep going.
Closing date right here, month, day, year.
If we keep going down, um,
Let's See.
So if there's anything specific that they wanted
to take from the property, um, they can,
so we're not gonna fill out any of this section.
Financing is going to be cash right here.
It's already checked. Let's keep going.
Title in escrow, whatever title company you're gonna be
using, you put their info right here, the name
of the company, the address, the email
of the escrow officer.
Keep going down. You'll need to,
buyer will need to sign all these areas.
You're gonna have to check if the property was built prior
to 1978 or if it was after.
Um, and you will just check whichever box,
um, applies to that.
And I usually put a little X there.
So I know when I go into DocuSign, um,
which one the buyer needs
to sign only he needs to sign that.
And then you'll see at the bottom of every page, buyer needs
to initial seller needs to initial, um,
on every single one of 'em.
So you sign, you are gonna initial every page on
DocuSign and so is the seller.
Um, and then this section, just the buyer, um, needs
to initial when the property was built.
Keep going down. Due diligence.
You're gonna put how many days, um, you agree
to right here in the inspection period.
Keep going down. So
buyer's gonna have to sign.
Um, all of these, this is just gonna be initials.
This is, uh, right here.
Is is the property on se, uh, sewer septic.
So you're gonna have to ask the seller
if it's on sewer septic.
It checks the bo check the box for either sewer system
or a conventional septic.
Um, all alternative system is very, very, very, very rare.
But if the seller says that you can check that box,
If We keep going down,
buyer declines the purchase of a home warranty plan.
Buyer's initial, you'll have to initial right here.
Keep going additional terms.
So we have, um, these additional terms in the event.
The buyer defaults sole remedy shall be the earnest money
deposit buyer's
and investor looking to purchase
the property for investment purposes.
The buyer will find the best fit for the property, including
but not limited to fixing, remodeling, adding onto,
rebuilding, reselling, wholesaling to an investment partner.
Leasing or converting
to a vacation rental buyer reserves the right to cancel
for any and all reasons during the inspection period.
Buyer to pay all title and escrow fees at closing.
So the reason we have this paragraph in there
is pretty much checks every single box, um,
that we would need to check, uh, for a property
for the different things we could do.
Um, but it also has the wholesaling language
that we legally need to have in the contract.
Um, and then this buyer reserves the right to cancel for any
and all reasons during the inspection period.
Protects us, um,
and allows us to be able to cancel these contracts, uh,
at any point during the inspection period
and get our earnest money back.
If we keep going down.
Seller and buyer are gonna need an initial.
So everywhere where it says seller
and buyer, there's gonna need
to be initials terms of acceptance.
Um, so that is how long you're giving them
to accept the contract.
Usually I do within 24 hours.
So, um, the next day, say the date's November 1st,
you're gonna put November 2nd at 5:00 PM um,
mountain standard time, right here, whatever date that is.
And you can tell the seller, Hey,
contract acceptance is until then.
So we need signatures before, um, that period.
Again, initials. Initials.
And then down here, this is all for agents.
So we don't need anything on here. Seller acceptance.
This is all agent information. So right here is the part.
We are gonna put the seller's, uh,
signature box on DocuSign.
Uh, the date, uh, of the contract being signed,
the seller's name printed.
You're gonna fill that out, uh, the address
of the property right here.
And then the city, state and zip code.
Um, so that is all the seller side,
and you'll be golden after you fill all that out.
And then the buyer's signature, this is gonna be
your signature, your entity, um,
and the entity's address right here.
And then you'll be good to go to fire it off to a seller
to get it signed.